Kara **Flaherty**

Web Developer & Visual Designer



karaflaherty.com kara.a.flaherty@gmail.com (347) 687-4128 Denver, CO

PROFILE

I emphasize test-driven development in all of my work with an eye toward clean and simple user experiences, beautiful and concise code, and well-documented version control. With learning as my top StrengthsFinder© skill, tackling new languages and frameworks is one of my favorite things to do to satisfy my constant curiosity for how things work.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ¡Query, Angular, React, Node.js, Bootstrap, Ruby, Rails, RSpec, REST API design, JSON, regex, AWS Lambda, Alexa Skills Kit, Firebase, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Wordpress, Google Analytics, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, UI/UX design, Agile principles

EDUCATION

University of Nebraska at Kearney | 2011 B.A. in Mass Media / Visual Communication & Design

Bloc | 2017 Full-Stack Web Development

Udacity/Grow With Google | 2018 Mobile Web Development

EXPERIENCE

DISH | Software Engineer

2/2018 - Current

Fortune 500 company in the direct broadcast satellite service industry and emerging leader in the IoT landscape

- Design and develop promotional email campaigns for both acquisition and retention campaigns that serve up to 2 million inboxes daily
- Collaborate with IoT teams to brainstorm and create smart campus solutions
- Hand code SVG elements in conjunction with the Parkifi team

Prairie Mountain Media | Page Designer & Editor

1/2017 - 2/2018

Design hub for over 20 Colorado and out-of-state newspapers and publications, including the Boulder Daily Camera, Denver Post, and St. Paul Pioneer Press

- Work with remote editors via Slack to organize, edit, and design the daily newspaper and special sections under tight production-critical deadlines
- Format content according to HTML tags and CSS stylesheets that automatically set print and web typography according to each paper's style
- Stand in as secondary editor to the Colorado Daily, which requires further HTML/CSS formatting of content to prepare it for the web and social media

Self-employed | Web & Graphic Designer

1/2009 - 12/2016

6/2012 - 12/2013

Freelance and contract work for independent publications, small businesses, and established marketing companies in the U.S., South Korea and Australia

- Join teams remotely to build websites, test user experiences, code custom plugins, create content, and design cohesive branding
- Troubleshoot design and database issues for Wordpress clients
- Design and implement marketing campaigns for email and social media

Scottsbluff Star-Herald | Multimedia Designer

Professional work in the advertising and multimedia departments at Scottsbluff's local newspaper with a circulation of more than 16,000

- Design, code, and ship marketing campaigns for email and social media
- Convert content from print to digital via HTML/CSS and the addition of photo galleries and related content to keep the newspaper's website up-to-date
- Utilize my web development skills for advertising clients who a) don't have a website, b) want a new website, or c) need help with their current website
- ★ As a new, much-needed income stream for the advertising department, web development became a permanent staple of the newspaper's digital media offerings for local advertisers based on my successful implementation.

RECENT PROJECTS

Alexa Skills | Developer

2018

Create and publish voice-enabled skills for the Amazon Alexa platform (github.com/karakarakaraff/alexa-skills)

- Clone and customize the Alexa fact sample for Kurt Vonnegut Quotes
- Clone, customize and debug the Alexa trivia sample for Stranger Things Trivia
- Write a custom Node.js Lambda function for The Oregon Trail game
- Utilize AWS Lambda, ASK-CLI, and the Amazon Developer Portal